Objects that are created from a class don't really last forever.
从类中创建的对象并非永远存在
Typically, you'd create an object from a class,
通常来说 我们从类中创建一个对象
fill its fields with some values,
用一些值来填充它的字段
and maybe create another object and fill its fields
又或许创建另一个对象
with some different values, but then eventually,
再用不同的值填充其字段
both those objects will get destroyed,
但这两个对象 连同字段中储存的每一个值
including every single value stored in those fields.
最终都会被销毁
Typically, that would happen whenever the scope of that object ends.
通常 对象作用域终止之时 该对象就会被销毁
For example here, inside this method,
比如在这个例子中 我在这个方法里
I've created the variable myItem,
创建了变量 myItem
which is an object of the type class Item.
作为 Item 类的一个对象
Once this method ends,
一旦该方法终止
this myItem variable doesn't exist anymore,
这个 myItem 变量
including all the values of all the field inside it.
包括其所有字段中的所有赋值 便不复存在
This kind of makes sense because you don't really need the values of
这其实也说得通 因为对于一个你根本都不会再访问的对象
a field inside an object that you can't even access anymore.
其所含字段的值也不是那么重要
However, in some rare occasions,
不过 少数情况下
you might want to store the value of
即使该类中并没有任何对象
a certain field even if there are no objects for that class.
你可能也希望储存某一字段的值
In that case, you need to add the keyword static when declaring this field.
这时 就需要在声明该字段时 添加关键词 static
Declaring a field as static means that these values are no longer
声明一个域为 static 就意味着这些值
stored within the object itself but within the class instead.
不再存储在这个对象本身 而是存储于类之中
Meaning that all objects of the class will share that same exact value.
也就是说 这个类的所有对象将会共享这个具体的值
And then even if every single object of the class has been destroyed,
也意味着 即使该类中的所有对象均被销毁
the value is still stored within the class.
这个值还是一直存储于这个类之中
If you decide to create a new object of that same class,
如果你要在同样的类中创建一个新的对象
then it will end up using the same value that was stored in the class.
则存储在类中的值最终也将用于新创建的对象
Notice however, that static here doesn't mean that the value doesn't change.
但请注意 这里的 static 并不代表这个值不会变
In fact, if that value does change,
实际上 如果这个值发生改变
it will update it in every single object of that class again.
则该类中的每一个对象都会随之更新
Now because static fields belong to classes instead of object,
由于静态字段作用于类 而非对象
Java allows you to access a static field directly from
Java 允许由类直接进入一个静态字段
the class instead of having to create an object of that class.
而无需创建该类的对象
For example here, I can access the power field
比如在这个例子中 我可以从 item 类直接进入 power 字段
from the class item directly and set it to a value.
并且设置一个值
Let's have a look at a coding example.
我们再以编码为例
In this example, I've created a class called Person,
在这个例子中 我创建可一个叫做“人”的类
and I'm trying to keep count of every single object that was created from the class.
我想计算该类中创建的所有对象的个数
So, I've added this public int field called count,
所以我加入了这个 public int 字段 将其命名为 count
and inside the constructor,
在构造函数内
which is just the default constructor,
就是默认的构造函数
I'm incrementing that count by one,
我用 1 做增量
which means that every time I create a new object of Person,
也就是说 我每创建一个新的人的对象
it will add one to that count variable.
count 变量就会加 1
Now if you go to the main method,
现在如果到主方法
you could see that I've created this loop that
就可以看到 我已经建立了
starts from zero and counts all the way to 100,
一共从 0 开始 一直到 100 的循环
and inside that loop,
在这个循环内
I'm creating a new instance of that class Person.
我要创建一个“人”类的新实例
And every time I create an object,
并且每当我创建一个对象
I print out the count value installed inside it.
都打印出在它里面安装的 count 值
So when I run this code,
所以 当我运行这个代码时
I would expect that every time I'm creating a new Person object,
我希望我每创建一个新的“人”类对象时
it's adding one to the counter,
计数器都会加 1
and by the time we reach to the hundredth Person,
当到达第 100 个人时
the count value would be 100.
count 值为 100
So I'm expecting to see the numbers between one and 100.
所以 我想看到的数字应该介于 1 和 100 之间
However, if I do run this code,
不过 如果我运行这个代码
it seems like I'm just getting a bunch of ones,
看起来我只是得到一些 1
which means that this count variable is not being updated at all.
也就是说 这个 count 变量并没有更新
The explanation for that is pretty simple.
原因很简单
If we go back to the Person class,
如果我们回到“人”这个类中
you'd notice that I haven't declared this count variable as static,
你会注意到 我并没有声明这个 count 变量为 static (静态)
which means that it belongs to the object not the class.
也就是说 它属于对象 而不是类
And because I'm creating a new object every time,
而且由于每次我创建一个新的对象
it means I'm creating a new variable called count and I'm only adding one to it.
其实都是在创建一个新的 count 变量 只是每个 count 变量都加 1
So every single object would have its own count variable that has the value one.
所以每个对象有自己的 count 变量 它的值为 1
However, if I do add the static keyword to our count variable here,
不过 如果我为 count 变量加上 static 关键词
this means that this variable now belongs to the class rather than the object.
那么这个变量现在就属于类 而不是对象
And every time I'm calling the constructor,
而且每次我调用构造函数时
it's adding one to the same variable count.
它会为同样的 count 变量加 1
So if I run this now,
所以 如果我现在再运行一次
I should get all the numbers between one and 100 like I expected earlier.
我会得到 1 到 100 之间的所有数字 这正是我之前想要看到的
Counting the instances that were created from a class is one
计算从类中创建的实例的个数
of the very common use cases for using the static keyword.
是 static 关键词的常用情形之一
So why don't you go ahead and try this yourself as well.
你也来试试看吧